Register of the Sino-Judaic Institute records
Hoover Institution Archives
Sino-Judaic Institute records
1910-2012
93031
Hoover Institution Archives
34 manuscript boxes, 1 oversized box (14.7 linear feet)
Memoirs, letters, personal identification documents, financial reports, bylaws, printed matter, photographs, and audiovisual material relating to Russian, Polish, other European Jews, and Jewish communal organizations in China, especially in Shanghai. Includes photocopy of a register of Polish citizens in China maintained by Polish consular officials from 1934 to 1942. Collected by the Sino-Judaic Institute.
Sino-Judaic Institute.
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1993, with increments received in 2013 and 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Founded in 1985 in Palo Alto, the Sino-Judaic Institute has sought to study and promote the ancient Jewish community of Kaifeng, China and to assist the descendants in reconnecting with their Jewish heritage. They also have actively worked with Chinese authorities to promote tourism to Kaifeng, open current exhibits on the Kaifeng Jews to the public, and promote Sino-Judaic relations. In keeping with these goals, the Sino-Judaic Institute has supported scholarly research and conferences, as well as tourism and travel to various locations in China.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Biographical Files contain memoirs, writings, identification documents, letters, drawings, photographs, school records, serials, clippings, and an oral history documenting Jewish communities in China, mainly in Shanghai, but also in Dalian, Harbin, and Kaifeng.
Research Materials consist of collected articles, letters, conference materials, brochures, lists, photographs, programs, reports, and a bibliography on Jews in China. Printed Matter consists of serial issues, pamphlets, and a directory. The Oversized File contains an album, lists, serials, and a register of Polish citizens in China. Videorecordings consists of videorecordings on VHS and DVD.
The 2013 Incremental Materials consist of printed matter, correspondence, institutional records, and exhibit records. Articles and printed matter include serials and scholarly articles by various authors, arranged alphabetically by author's surname or article title. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent or subject. Institutional records of the Sino-Judaic Institute, focusing on the years 1985 to 2007, but also including materials dating back to 1964, include board meeting minutes, founding documentation, institutional correspondence, proposals, and other records. The exhibit records include records, notes, and correspondence regarding "The Jews of Kaifeng" traveling museum exhibit.
The 2014 Incremental Materials include correspondence and institutional records, arranged alphabetically.
Chinese names have been indexed as spelled, with the family name preceding the given name and no comma used.
Related Collections
Rena Krasno papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Benjamin Michael Levaco papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Fred Marcus papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Matook Nissim papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Gerd Wallenstein papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Jews--China.; Russians--China.; Shanghai (China)
- Biographical Files, 1910-2002 (Box 1-5)
  Scope and Contents Note
  In alphabetical order by surname.
  - Avshalomov, Aaron, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Bernikoff, Alex, 1910-1949 (Box-folder 1: 2-7)
    Includes photographs of the Russian Jewish community in Harbin, Shanghai, and Dalian.
  - Bettelheim family, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 1: 8-9)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes memoir by Lilli Bettelheim.
  - Bratmann, Friedrich, 1940s (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Callmann, Erich, 1940-2002 (Box-folder 1: 11-15)
    Includes diary fragment and selected issues of Ostasiatischer Lloyd, Shanghai Post, The Shanghai Times, Shanghai Echo, and Die Neue Zeit from 1940-1945.
  - Cohen, Joseph, 1997 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Cohen, Morris, 2001 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    Essay by Rena Krasno and photograph of Morris' grave.
  - Collins, Henry, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Edwards, Tamara Veselovzorova, after 1986 (Box-folder 1: 19)
    Writings on the lives of Russian women in Japanese prisoner-of-war camps near Shanghai.
  - Friedmann, John and Alice, 1938-1995 (Box-folder 1: 20-21)
    Includes two biographical essays, "I Looked Out of the Window and the Chestnuts Were Blooming: The Story of Alice Friedmann" and "From Buchenwald to Shanghai: The Story of John (Hans) Friedmann," written by Rena Krasno.
  - Gabow, Leo, 1982-1998 (Box-folder 1: 22-23, Box-folder 2: 1-4)
    Relates mainly to Chinese Jews in Kaifeng.
  - Halle, Rolf von, 1946 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Hamel, Gerhard, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Hanin, Leo, undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Heppner, Ernest G., undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
    Includes deed of gift from Ernest G. Heppner to the United States Holocaust Memorial Council.
  - Hilally, Estelle, 1943, undated (Box-folder 2: 9)
    Includes Hilally's notebooks from the Cathedral School for Girls in Shanghai.
  - Ilutovich, Leon, 1939-2000 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Isaack, John L. and Harriet, 1936-1945 (Box-folder 2: 11-12)
    Includes a memoir and photographs of Shanghai street scenes.
  - Jacob-Ezekiel family, 1948-2000 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Jedeikin family, 1937-1995 (Box-folder 3: 2-10)
    Includes a memoir and selected issues of In Uno Bulletin, published by the Public & Thomas Hanbury School for Boys from 1941-1945. See also: Oversize File.
  - Kaffel, Raphael, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Kauffmann, Fritz, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 12)
    Includes "The Experience of the Shanghai Jewish Community Under the Japanese in World War II."
  - Keidermann, Arthur, undated (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Kipen, Israel, 1943, 1989, undated (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Kraemer, Herbert and Fanny, 1929-1949 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Less, John H., 1990s (Box-folder 3: 16)
    Includes "Holocaust Refugee in Shanghai, China, 1940-1947: Notes, Drawings, and Records."
  - Levy, D. B., 1943-1944 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    Contains school notebooks written while interned at the Pootung (Pudong) Civil Assembly Center, Shanghai.
  - Lewin, Heinz and Gerda, 1938-1994 (Box-folder 4: 2)
    Includes Rules and Regulations for the Shanghai Volunteer Corps, 1939.
  - Lowenstein, Julius, undated (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Manski, Samuel, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    Includes Chiune Sugihara visa.
  - Ochert, Morris S., undated (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Patent, Mavel, 1934-1949, 1997 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    Includes photographs of staff at RCA Victor, Shanghai.
  - Pollack, Curt M., 1945-1987 (Box-folder 4: 7-8)
    Includes materials relating to the Broh and Kohn families.
  - Pulvermacher family, 1939-1998 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Schwartz, Dinah, undated (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Sonnemann, Kurt, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Soroka, Margery, 1947 July-October (Box-folder 5: 2)
    Letters and photographs relating to the Chinese-Jewish community in Kaifeng.
  - Steiner, Sebastian, 1983 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    Includes oral history on compact sound cassette.
  - Tonn, Willy, undated (Box-folder 5: 4-5)
  - Wallenstein, Gerd, 1987 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    Contains "Transnational Destiny: A Documentary of a European's Sinification Under Adversity."
- Research Materials, 1929-2007 (Box 5-6)
  In alphabetical order by physical form.
  - Bibliography, "Japanese and Chinese Materials Pertaining to the Jewish Catastrophe, 1939-1945,", 1955 (Box-folder 5: 7-8)
  - Brochure, Center for Jewish Studies, Shanghai, 2007 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Collected articles on Polish and Austrian refugees in Shanghai, 1940s (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Conference materials, "Flucht nach Shanghai," Salzburg, Austria, 1995 May 26-28 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Letters, 1929, 1990s
    - Shanghai Zionist Association, 1929 June 3 (Box-folder 5: 12)
    - Yeshua Synagogue, Burma, 1990s (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Lists, 1934-1990s
    - Guests on S.S. President Coolidge voyage, 1934 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Jewish associations in Shanghai, 1938 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Jewish graves in Harbin, China, 1990s (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - Jewish graves in Yokohama Foreigners' Cemetery, Japan, 1990s (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Jews in Tsingtao, China, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - Shanghai Jewish club members, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Photographs, 1936-1999
    - Hongkou, Shanghai, by Hillary Farkas, 1999 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - Italian naval officers in Shanghai, 1941 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - Members of the Jewish Company of the Shanghai Volunteer Corps, 1936 December 10 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Programs, Shanghai Jewish School and Jewish Ladies Benevolent Society, 1938 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Reports, Council of the Jewish Community, Shanghai, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Table of contents, "The Great Geographical Discoveries and China," by Zhang Yidong, undated (Box-folder 6: 12)
- Printed Matter, 1927-2007 (Box 6-7)
  In alphabetical order by title.
  - Bulletin, Igud Yotzei Sin (The Association of Former Residents of China in Israel), nos. 381, 384, 389, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 6: 13-15)
    Includes English, Russian, and Hebrew editions.
  - Directory of Individuals Interested in the Jews and the Jewish Communities of East, Southeast, and South Asia, compiled and edited by Frank Joseph Shulman, 1993 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Emigranten Adressbuch Shanghai, November 1939, reprinted, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - The Future, published by the Shanghai Jewish Youth Community Center, vol. 1, nos. 8, 11, 1947 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - The Hongkew Chronicle, vols. 1-7, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - Israel-China Voice of Friendship, no. 52, 2005 July-August (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Japan und die Juden: Studie über die Judenpolitik des Kaiserreiches Japan während der Zeit des Nationalsozialismus 1933-1945, by Heinz Eberhard Maul, 2000 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Jewish Schools in Baghdad, 1832-1974: Picture Album, edited by Zvi Yehuda, 1996 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Mutzl and Uli: The Story of My Parents, undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Nehardea: Journal of the Babylonian Jewry Heritage Center, no. 11, 1998 November (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Points East, vols. 20-21, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Prayer book, Beth Aharon Synagogue, Shanghai, 1927 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - The Scribe: Journal of Descendants of Babylonian Jewry, 1971-1993 (Box-folder 7: 6-7)
  - "So This Is Shanghai," photobook, 1935 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - The Story of Joseph P. Weber, circa 1991 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - The Story of a Haven: The Jews in Shanghai, Jewish Museum of Australia, 1997 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - "Survival and Progress: Shanghai Reunion,", 1980 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - StuDeo: Studienwerk Deutsches Leben in Ostasien, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 7: 12)
    Includes 3.5" computer disk containing StuDeo's catalogue.
  - The Trial and Conviction of U.S. Spies in Peking: The Texts of the Indictment and Verdict, 1951 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Unzer velt, 1946 March 8 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Ustav russkogo obshchestva Vzaimnogo Kredita v g. Shankhai, 1941 (Box-folder 7: 15)
- Oversize File, 1933-1949 (Box 8)
  In alphabetical order by physical form or title.
  - By physical form, 1934-1949
    - Album of newspaper clippings collected by Joseph Jedeikin, 1942-1945
    - Booklet on Harbin, China, circa 1949
    - List of Jewish families in Shanghai, 1943
      Photocopy from the Shanghai Municipal Police files held at the U.S. National Archives.
    - Plan of old Jewish cemetery in Harbin, China, undated
    - Register of Polish citizens in China maintained by Polish consular officials, 1934-1942
  - By title, 1933-1941
    - Israel's Messenger: The International Jewish Monthly Official Organ of the Shanghai Zionist Association and the Jewish National Fund Commission for China, vol. 38, no. 8-9, 1941 November-December
    - The Jewish Call: Monthly Publication Issued by Shanghai Zionists Revisionists, vol. 1, nos. 1-5, 1933
    - Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury: Pictorial Review of Local Hostilities, vol. 1, nos. 1-2, 1937 September 6-10
      Photographs of "Bloody Saturday" in Shanghai.
- Videorecordings, 1927-2006 (Box 9)
  - Escape to Shanghai, 1 videocassette (VHS), 1998
  - Escape to Shanghai, directed by Dietmar Schulz and Horst Eisfelder, 1 electronic optical disc (DVD), 2004
  - Escape to the Rising Sun, directed by Diana Perelsztejn, 1 videocassette (VHS), 1990
  - "John Friedman Interviewed by Cheryl Miller re Holocaust, Shanghai Refugees," 1 videocassette (VHS), 1990 October 30
  - Legendary Sin Cities: Shanghai, 1 electronic optical disc (DVD), 2005
  - Port of Last Resort, 1 videocassette (VHS), 1998
  - "Reuter's Video of Clinton China Visit," 2 videocassettes (VHS), 1990s
  - Round Eyes in the Middle Kingdom, directed by Ronald Levaco, 1 videocassette (VHS), 1995
  - Sanctuary Shanghai, directed by Chen Yifei and He Xiao Lu, 1 videocassette (VHS), 1998
    Includes interviews with Michael Blumenthal and Kurt Duldner.
  - "Shanghai 1927," 1 videocassette (VHS)
    Home movies of Shanghai recorded by Samuel Ladenheim
  - "Shanghai's Ohel Moishe Synagogue," 1 videocassette (VHS), 1999 August
  - "Testimony to the Truth: Alice Friedman," interviewed by Cheryl Miller, 1 videocassette (VHS), 1990 October 30
  - Tientsin Diaries, directed by Serge Gregory, Vaskino, 1 electronic optical disc (DVD), 2006
  - "Zerah (Polish Jews)," 1 videocassette (VHS), undated
  - The Battle of China, directed by Frank Capra and Anatole Litvak, 1 videocassette (VHS), 1986
- 2013 Incremental Materials, 1964-2012 (Box 10-32)
  - Articles and printed matter, 1966-2012
    Includes books, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, and articles regarding China, Judaism, and Jewish people in China.
    - Points East, 1987-2007 (Box-folder 10: 1-5)
    - Article in Chinese, undated (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Brown, David, articles by and about him, undated (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - Xu Buzeng, "Jewish Influence on the Musical Life of Shanghai,", 1992 (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - Cahen, Claude, article by, undated (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Chalier, Agnes, article by, 1992 (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Chan Sui Jeung, "Jews in Kaifeng: Past and Present,", undated (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - "China and the Jewish People,", 2004 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - China-Judaic Connection, 1993 (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - Dehergne, Joseph and Donald D. Leslie, "Juifs de Chine: à Travers la Correspondance Inédite des Jésuites du Dix-Huitième Siècle,", 1980 (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - Directory and Guide to Jewish Shanghai, 2001 (Box-folder 11: 10)
    - Dien, Albert E., "Report on a Visit to China,", 1990s (Box-folder 11: 11)
    - Eber, Irene, article by, 1972 (Box-folder 11: 12)
    - Eber, Irene, "Overland and By Sea: Eight Centuries of the Jewish Presence in China," by Irene Eber, 2005 (Box-folder 11: 13)
    - Escroignard, Victor, article by, undated (Box-folder 11: 14)
    - Fine, David, article by, 1992 (Box-folder 11: 15)
    - Forever Nostalgia - The Jews in Shanghai, pamphlet, 1998 (Box-folder 11: 16)
    - Frank, Benis M., article by, 1992 (Box-folder 11: 17)
    - Goldman, Rene, article by, 1994 (Box-folder 11: 18)
    - Gong Fangzhen, article by, undated (Box-folder 11: 19)
    - Pan Guang, "Development of Jewish and Israel Studies in China,", 1994 (Box-folder 11: 20)
    - Pan Guang, "A New Quest for Refugees,", undated (Box-folder 11: 21)
    - Pan Guang, "Zionism in Shanghai,", undated (Box-folder 11: 22)
    - Harvard conference papers, 1992 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - "The History of Harbin Jewish Community,", 1991 (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - Hoberman, Barry, "The Early Jews in China: The Origin of the Jewish Community of K'aifeng,", 1973 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - Horal, Phyllis, "Cemeteries of the Kaifeng Jews,", 1992 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - "How the Sino-Judaic Institute Began and a History of Its Accomplishments Through 2012,", circa 2012 (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - Irwin, Sara, "Artifacts in the Collection of the Royal Ontario Museum Associated with the Jewish Community of Kaifeng,", 1997 (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Zhu Jiang, articles by, 1983 (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - Katz, David, "The Chinese Jews and the Problem of Biblical Authority in Eighteenth and Nineteenth Century England,", 1991 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - Katz, Nathan, "The Judaisms of Kaifeng and Cochin: Parallel and Divergent Styles of Religious Acculturation,", 1995 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Kaifeng Jews, articles about, undated (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - Kling, Ruth, "Jewish Textile Crafts in Kaifeng,", 1993 (Box-folder 12: 11)
      Includes correspondence and commentary.
    - Kroker, Bruno, "The Last of China's Jews,", 1990s (Box-folder 12: 12)
    - Kumaraswamy, P. R., "The Star and the Dragon: an Overview of Israeli-PRC Military Relations,", undated (Box-folder 12: 13)
    - Laytner, Anson, "Alive But Not So Well and Living in Kaifeng,", 1981 (Box-folder 12: 14)
    - Lazare, Bernard, "Miroir des Legendes,", undated (Box-folder 12: 15)
    - Leslie, Donald D., "Persia or Yemen? The Origins of the Kaifeng Jews,", 1982 (Box-folder 12: 16)
    - Leslie, Donald D., research and articles by, 1967-1980 (Box-folder 12: 17)
    - Leventhal, Dennis, "Sino-Judaic Studies: Whence and Where?,", undated (Box-folder 12: 18)
    - Pan Ling, "In Search of Old Shanghai,", 1990s (Box-folder 12: 19)
    - Neubauer, A., "Jews in China,", 1966 (Box-folder 12: 20)
    - Old China Hands Archive, pamphlet, California State University Northridge, 2002 (Box-folder 12: 21)
    - Pollak, Michael, "A Preliminary Study of Twelve Detached Skins from a Centuries-Old Chinese Torah Scroll,", 2001 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Song Nai Rhee, "Jewish Assimilation: The Case of Chinese Jews,", 1973 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Schermerhorn, R. A., "Jews Without Middleman Status - Their Historic Position in China and India,", 1981 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - Schwarcz, Vera, "Chinese History and Jewish Memory,", undated (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - Gao Wangzhi, "On the History of Judaism in China,", undated (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - Zhao Xiangru, "Some Issues Concerning the Chinese Jews,", 1992 (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Gu Xiaoming, article by, 1989 (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - Xu Xin, "Chinese Research on Jewish Diasporas in China,", undated (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - Xu Xin, The Jews of Kaifeng, China: History, Culture, and Religion, 2003 (Box-folder 13: 9)
    - Wang Yisha, article by, 1992 (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - Tang Yusheng, articles by, undated (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Correspondence, 1964-2007
    Includes institutional correspondence and records, arranged alphabetically.
    - Addresses, 1987 (Box-folder 13: 12)
    - Asia Pacific Jewish Association, 1995 (Box-folder 13: 13)
    - Asian Rare Books, 1992 (Box-folder 13: 14)
    - Auerbach, Arnold J., 1994 (Box-folder 13: 15)
    - Austria, "Refuge in Shanghai" conference, 1994 (Box-folder 13: 16)
    - Babylonian Jewry Heritage Center, 1997 (Box-folder 13: 17)
    - Babylonian Museum, 2000 (Box-folder 13: 18)
    - Bar-Gal, Dvir, 2006 (Box-folder 13: 19)
    - Bar-ner, Uri, 1994 (Box-folder 13: 20)
    - "Is There Jewish Life in Beijing?,", undated (Box-folder 13: 21)
    - Belzer, Rabbi Arnold, 1985-1994 (Box-folder 13: 22)
    - Berlin Aktives Museum, 1997 (Box-folder 13: 23)
    - Berlin, Moishe, 1995 (Box-folder 13: 24)
    - The Philip and Muriel Berman Foundation, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 13: 25)
    - Berman, Robin, 1994 (Box-folder 13: 26)
    - Berton, Peter, 1997 (Box-folder 13: 27)
    - Betta, Chiara, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 13: 28)
    - Betta, Chiara, 1990-1994 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
      Includes photographs.
    - Bialik, Loren J., 1992 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Biblio Press, 1990 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Bing, Professor D., 1993 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Birobidzhan, undated (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Blader, Susan, 1991 (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Blady, Ken, undated (Box-folder 14: 9)
    - Blumenthal, Michael, 1995 (Box-folder 14: 10)
    - Book distribution, 1996 (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - Book Peddler, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 14: 12)
    - Bookseller Twersky, 1991 (Box-folder 14: 13)
    - Bowman, Tzviia, 1993 (Box-folder 14: 14)
    - Bransten, Edward, 1989 (Box-folder 14: 15)
    - Bresler, Boris, 1994 (Box-folder 14: 16)
    - Bridges to China, 1989 (Box-folder 14: 17)
    - Buxbaum, David, 1985 (Box-folder 14: 18)
    - Canada, National Library, 1995 (Box-folder 14: 19)
    - Center for Israel Studies, 1990 (Box-folder 14: 20)
    - Center for Judaic Culture in China, undated (Box-folder 14: 21)
    - Central Conference of American Rabbis, 1993 (Box-folder 14: 22)
    - Central Zionist Archives, 1995 (Box-folder 14: 23)
    - Chalier, Agnes, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 14: 24)
    - Chan Sui Jeung, 1988-1995 (Box-folder 14: 25)
    - Chang Shoou-Huey, 1997 (Box-folder 14: 26)
    - Chang Zheng, 1991 (Box-folder 14: 27)
    - Chu Chem, 1989 (Box-folder 14: 28)
    - Chen Libo, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 14: 29)
    - China Association for International Friendly Liaison, 1989 (Box-folder 14: 30)
    - China attitudes toward Jews, 1997 (Box-folder 14: 31)
    - "China Connection,", 1990-1998 (Box-folder 14: 32)
    - China Judaic Studies Association, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 14: 33)
    - China Scholars, 2003 (Box-folder 14: 34)
    - Chinese Cultural Center, 1998 (Box-folder 14: 35)
    - Chinese Jews, undated (Box-folder 14: 36)
    - Christians in China, 1991 (Box-folder 14: 37)
    - Chu, Francis, 1991 (Box-folder 14: 38)
    - Cohen, Aaron, 1995 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Cohen, Marc, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Cohen-Myers, Paolo, 1993 (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Cohen, Two Gun, 2003 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Cohn, Robert, 1991 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Community organizations, 1991 (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - Conference on Women's Rights, circa 1990s (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - Cooper, Abraham, 1994 (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - Cooper, Alanna E., 1994 (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - Cornell University Press, 1991 (Box-folder 15: 10)
    - Cornwall, Claudia, 1992 (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - Council on the Jewish Experience in Shanghai, undated (Box-folder 15: 12)
    - Daniel, Samuel, 1990 (Box-folder 15: 13)
    - Cao Dapeng, 1993 (Box-folder 15: 14)
    - Davidson, Edward, 2002 (Box-folder 15: 15)
    - Dead Sea Scrolls, 1992 (Box-folder 15: 16)
    - Denenberg, Marshall, 1998 (Box-folder 15: 17)
    - Dien, Albert, 1991 (Box-folder 15: 18)
    - Donations, 1992 (Box-folder 15: 19)
    - Dong, Sager, 1993 (Box-folder 15: 20)
    - Drake, Dr. F. S., undated (Box-folder 15: 21)
    - Dray-Novey, Alison, 1999 (Box-folder 15: 22)
    - Dryfuss, Jessica, 1991 (Box-folder 15: 23)
    - East House, 1991 (Box-folder 15: 24)
    - Eber, Irene, 1995 (Box-folder 15: 25)
    - Eckstein, Mathew, 1998 (Box-folder 15: 26)
    - Edelman, undated (Box-folder 15: 27)
    - Eisenberg, 1991 (Box-folder 15: 28)
    - Elazar, Daniel, 1991 (Box-folder 15: 29)
    - Emunah of America, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 15: 30)
    - Encyclopedia project, 1990s (Box-folder 15: 31)
    - Epstein, Israel, interview, 1990s (Box-folder 15: 32)